welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using the free software
使用免费软件的教程
kdenlive in this video i'm going to be
在这段视频中 我将成为
showing you my workflow for using
向您展示我的工作流程以使用
kdenlive when i edit my youtube videos
当我编辑我的YouTube视频时kdenlive
to upload them to youtube so what I have
把它们上传到YouTube上 所以我有
is actually a couple different videos I
实际上是几个不同的视频我
have my intro screen looks like this
让我的简介屏幕看起来像这样
it's just one mp4 video and I also have
这只是一个MP4视频 我还有
my outro screen it looks like this and
我的Otro屏幕看起来是这样的
it's just out row that plays for I
只有一排在外面为我打球
believe 6 seconds and this is where my
相信6秒 这就是我的
videos go this is a nothing's happening
视频走了这是一个什么都没有发生的事情
here but I still made a video just
在这里 但我还是做了一段视频
because so I'm going to drag both of
因为我要把两个人都拖走
these in to my project bin and then most
把这些放到我的项目垃圾箱里 然后大多数
of the time I actually don't have to so
我其实不需要这么做的时间
I'm recording with OBS I'm recording
我在用OBS录音 我在录音
right now this is my screen recording
现在这是我的屏幕记录
that I'm doing to do this video but also
我正在做的这段视频 但也
I mean when those are done I everything
我的意思是 当这些都做完了 我就什么都做了
go it gets saved to this OBS video
Go它被保存到这个OBS视频中
folder on a separate 500 gigabyte hard
单独的500 GB硬盘上的文件夹
drive on my computer so this is the
我电脑上的驱动器 所以这是
video I'm recording right now but if I
我现在正在录制视频 但如果我
these are all the like the kdenlive
这些都很像kdenlive
tutorials I've been making and a couple
我一直在制作的教程和一些
of them needs some edits so this lesson
其中一些需要编辑 所以这一课
8 one needs an edit all the rest of my
一个人需要编辑我剩下的所有内容
backs are pretty good to go but so I'm
背部很好 但我想
going to do the lesson 8 1 so will bring
去做第八课 这样会带来
less than 8 in and the reason it needs
不到8英寸及其需要的原因
an edit is the only part I want to edit
编辑是我唯一想要编辑的部分
from this one was speaking up the
从这一次开始 我就大声说出了
rendering time I think I rendered out a
渲染时间我想我渲染了一个
video and it took about a minute and a
视频 花了大约一分钟零一分钟
half I just didn't want to have you the
一半我只是不想让你成为
viewer be waiting a minute and a half so
观众等了一分半钟
I'm just gonna speed that portion of the
我只想加快这部分的速度
video up so I'll show you how to do that
把视频放上去 我来教你怎么做
so first of all I want to drag in oh and
所以 首先 我想要拖入哦和
also so all these video clips if you
还有 如果你能看到这些视频片段
have VLC installed you can check but I
是否安装了VLC 您可以查看 但我
go to play the video back to another
转到将视频播放到另一个视频
video and we can go to or dad tools and
视频 我们可以访问或爸爸工具和
then codec information under VLC if you
那么VLC下的编解码器信息如果您
have VLC installed and it will tell you
安装VLC后 它会告诉您
so this is 1920 by 1080 awesome the
所以这是1920年到1080年令人惊叹
frame rate is 60 frames per second
帧速率为每秒60帧
awesome and this is like just some more
太棒了 这就像是更多的
information about it and so actually all
关于它的信息 所以实际上所有的
of my video
我的视频的
our that so if I go to my other ones
我们的 所以如果我去我其他的
like this
就像这样
outro even though it's just a still
Otro 尽管它只是一个蒸馏器
nothing's happening we can just we can
什么都没发生我们可以只是我们可以
still go to codec information and look
仍然转到编解码器信息并查看
alright 60fps 1920 by 1080 so I made
好的 60fps 1920x1080年 所以我做了
sure that all of my video clips are 60
我确定我所有的视频剪辑都是60
frames per second 1920 by 1080 and for a
1920乘以1080的每秒帧数 以及
screenshot 60fps is really kind of
截图60fps真的是一种
overkill I'm still deciding I'll
过度杀伤力我仍在决定我会
probably go back down to 30
可能会回落到30
but for now I'm doing 60fps so what I
但现在我的速度是60fps 所以我
need to do is go to my project project
需要做的就是转到我的项目项目
settings and change my project to a
设置并将我的项目更改为
60fps 1080p project changing the profile
60fps 1080p项目更改配置文件
on your project cannot be undone okay
在您的项目上无法撤消 好吗？
continue so perfect there we go if I
如果我继续如此完美 我们将继续前进
wouldn't have done that I would have had
我就不会那么做了
issues I would have been creating a
我会制造的问题
video that was 30 frames per second
每秒30帧的视频
using footage that was 60 frames per
使用每帧60帧的素材
second so I would have had some sync
第二秒 这样我就会有一些同步
issues with my audio and it would have
我的音频出了问题 它会
not been pretty alright so first of all
不是很好 所以首先
I'm going to drag in my intro and put it
我要把我的介绍拖进来 把它
on video track 1
在视频轨道1上
I started at 0 seconds there then I'm
我从0秒开始 然后我
gonna grab in my main part of the video
我要抓住我视频的主要部分
and just put it right here and I'll
把它放在这里 我就会
scroll to the end of this video it's
滚动到这段视频的结尾
quite long and I'll put my outro right
很久了 我会把我的越轨纠正过来
at the end and actually outro I usually
在最后 实际上超过了我通常
like to put up on track 2 and overlap it
喜欢放在2号轨道上 然后重叠在一起
a little bit so this is ooh man let's do
有一点 所以这就是哦 伙计 我们开始吧
what we'll do the intro first actually
实际上 我们首先要做的是介绍
so let me come here whoa where's it at
所以让我来这里哇它在哪里
alright so I'm just going to watch and
好的 那我就看着吧
see how it looks with my intro and
看看我的介绍看起来怎么样
transitioning into the video welcome
过渡到视频欢迎
back some green flashes but that I think
回来一些绿色的闪光 但我认为
it's just gonna happen in my play black
这只会发生在我的黑色戏剧中
play back welcome back I don't think
回放欢迎回放我不认为
those green flashes will be there but
那些绿色的闪光会在那里 但是
we'll see for sure
我们一定会看到的
ok so I had a little bit of a little bit
好的 所以我有一点
of time here so I'm gonna actually
在这里的时间 所以我实际上
shorten this just a teeny tiny bit to
把这个稍微缩短一点就行了
get rid of that little click
去掉那个小小的滴答声
welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
perfect so this is how this will start
太好了 这就是开始的方式
and then at some point in this video I
然后在这段视频中的某个点上我
need to actually edit I gotta find this
我需要实际编辑 我必须找到这个
the part that I'm exporting out and I'm
我要出口的那部分 我是
just gonna speed up the video during
只是要在视频播放过程中加快速度
that portion so let me find that real
所以让我找到真实的那部分
quick oh this is it right here perfect
快点 哦 是不是就在这里 太好了
so I can see on the screen that it's
所以我可以在屏幕上看到
doing it okay so let's go back a little
做得很好 所以让我们往回倒一点
bit before see what's happening at this
在看这发生了什么之前
portion let's go to render will render
让我们去渲染的部分将被渲染
it select the zone and we'll save it to
它会选择该区域 我们会将其保存到
the desktop and we'll call it a whoops
桌面 我们称它为呼呼
we'll just call it something and then
我们就叫它什么 然后
we'll make sure it's an mp4 I like to
我们会确保这是我喜欢的MP4
you could do WebM but
你可以做WebM 但是
mp4 is kind of this a good standard for
MP4在某种程度上是一个很好的标准
uploading to like Facebook or YouTube
上传到Facebook或YouTube
video we render this out okay so right
我们把这段视频渲染出来 好的 所以对
here after I said I want to pause the
在我说了我想暂停之后
video while we render it out I'm going
视频 当我们呈现它的时候 我要去
to grab my razor tool I'm going to cut
为了拿起我的剃须刀 我要切开
the video clip right here I'm gonna play
我要播放的视频剪辑就在这里
well not really play actually I guess I
嗯 其实不是真的玩 我想我
can just skip forward and look I can
我可以向前跳过 然后看我能做到的
kind of see that progress bar so I want
我看到了进度条 所以我想
to go tell the progress bar is
去告诉进度条是
completely done or almost done even grab
完全完成或几乎完成甚至抓取
it right there and then I will grab my
就在那里 然后我会拿起我的
razor tool and cut the video again then
剃须刀工具 然后再次剪切视频
go to my selection tool select this
转到我的选择工具选择此选项
video and I could just I could just
视频和我可以只是我可以只是
delete this all the way out but maybe
把这些全部删除 但也许
just kind of be fun let's just apply a
只是有点好玩 让我们只申请一个
speed effect and let's actually have it
速度效果 让我们真正拥有它
oops I've done effect speed and we'll
哦 我已经做了效果速度 我们将
drag speed down onto this and we'll just
把速度拖到这上面 我们就
make it be a thousand percent instead of
让它成为1000%而不是
a hundred percent perfect now it's nice
百分百完美 现在很好
and short and now I think we can play
很短 现在我想我们可以玩了
and see but it might be a little bit
你看 但这可能有一点
laggy the video
滞后的视频
and it'll actually play a lot faster
而且它实际上会播放得更快
than that okay so that took about the 47
比那个好的 所以这花了大约47
let me see how fast this is yeah in fact
让我看看这有多快是的事实上
I'm gonna do two thousand percent you
我会尽我所能帮你
guys as time is valuable
伙计们 时间是宝贵的
let's make this super short okay there
我们长话短说吧 好吗？
we go alright and then I have to go back
我们走得很好 然后我就得回去
and because I just kind of shortened
因为我刚刚缩短了
this video a little bit I'm going to
这个视频 我要讲一点
bring my outro and put it right here and
把我的Otro拿过来放在这里
the reason I overlap it a little bit is
我将其稍微重叠的原因是
just because it's usually a little bit
只是因为它通常会有一点
of empty space or silent space at the
空旷的空间或寂静的空间
end of my videos next one okay so
我的视频结束了 下一个好的 那么
actually about right I guess this didn't
实际上差不多 我想这不是
have a whole lot maybe that's good but I
有很多 也许这很好 但我
bet I catch on next one cool all right
我打赌我会赶上下一个酷的
I'm gonna render this out and I guess
我要把它呈现出来 我想
this is gonna be a similar situation
这将是一个类似的情况
because this is gonna take a while to
因为这需要一段时间
render I don't click render and we're
渲染我没有点击渲染 我们正在
gonna go to mp4 we're gonna choose the
我们会选择MP4 我们会选择
file name so I will render it - I'm
文件名 所以我将呈现它-我是
gonna put it here I'll put it in this
我要把它放在这里 我要把它放进这个
folder right here I'll just call it Kade
文件夹就在这里 我就叫它Kade
and live lesson 8 fixed and I'll hit
现场直播第八课修好了 我会按下
save alright so mp4 it's gonna render
保存好 这样MP4就会呈现出来
according to our project settings with
根据我们的项目设置
this which is 60 frames per second 1920
这是每秒60帧1920
by 1080 and I'll hit render to file and
到1080年 我将点击渲染到文件和
then I'm gonna have to also pause this
那我还得暂停一下
video and speed it up so it's just like
视频和速度 所以它就像
a never-ending video editing project but
一个永无止境的视频编辑项目
I'm curious here so it says waiting it's
我很好奇 所以上面写着等待
actually taking a little bit of a second
实际上花了一点时间
to get this going I wonder why okay
为了让这一切开始 我想知道为什么好吧
there it goes so it's gonna be 23
它在那里 所以它将是23
minutes to render out this nine minute
几分钟来渲染这九分钟
video that's interesting okay so that's
很有趣的视频 好的 所以这就是
done encoding now and we can close this
现在已经完成编码 我们可以关闭此
we can go and take a look and see where
我们可以去看看 看看哪里
our finished product looks like make
我们的成品看起来像是
sure doesn't have those green flashing
当然不会有那些绿色的闪烁
things so this is the file
所以这就是文件
welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using the free software
使用免费软件的教程
kdenlive in this video we're going to be
Kdenlive在这段视频中我们将成为
and I like to actually skip forward a
实际上 我喜欢跳过一个
little bit I have to watch certain parts
有一点 我不得不注意某些部分
of it sometimes certain objects like
有时某些物体 比如
transparent layers not in kdenlive just
不在kdenlive中的透明层只是
in video in general sometimes certain
在一般的视频中 有时某些
portions of video don't display the way
视频的某些部分显示方式不同
you think they're going to so I just
你觉得他们会这样做 所以我只是
like to go through and watch and listen
喜欢穿行、观看和聆听
make sure the audio is on track with
确保音频在音轨上
everything and then that way I know it's
所有的一切 然后我知道这是
a good video and this looks like it's
一段很好的视频 这看起来像是
good cool
好酷
very good so that's my workflow using
非常好 这就是我使用的工作流程
kdenlive and actually I'll release
Kdenlive 实际上我会释放
another video but just recently I
另一段视频 但就在最近
started using a batch script or like a
开始使用批处理脚本或类似于
shell script to do batching batch
用于执行批处理的外壳脚本
editing on these videos so now what I do
编辑这些视频 所以现在我要做的是
I just take the entire folder and I just
我只是拿了整个文件夹 然后我就
have a little script that uses ffmpeg
我有一个使用ffmpeg的小脚本
and it goes through and actually just
它通过了 实际上就是
adds the intro and the outro to every
将前奏和结尾添加到每个
one of them I'm still kind of
他们中的一个 我仍然是某种
fine-tuning it but when I get that
微调它 但当我得到它
working really well I'll release a video
工作真的很好 我会发布一个视频
and show you that workflow saves a ton
并向您展示工作流可节省大量成本
of time not having to edit all of them
不需要编辑所有内容的时间
and actually I'm trying to get it so I
事实上 我正在试着得到它 所以我
don't have to actually re-encode so
不需要真正地重新编码
instead of waiting like 20 minutes to
而不是等上20分钟
encode on the processor I can just
在处理器上编码 我只需
actually add in since they're all mp4s I
实际上加上了 因为他们都是mp4
can actually just add them all together
实际上只需把它们加在一起
and it's a very quick process anyway
不管怎么说 这是一个非常快的过程
that's my workflow for kdenlive
这就是我在kdenlive上的工作流程
appreciate you watching like and
感谢您的收看点赞和
subscribe if you found this informative
如果您觉得这篇文章内容丰富 请订阅
and I'll catch you on the next video
我会在下一个视频中看到你